globalcareersfair.com 2019-03-09

# Privacy Policy - Global Careers Fair

We operate the website [www.globalcareersfair.com](https://www.globalcareersfair.com/).

We are Global Careers Spain SL, a company registered in Spain under CIF number B54959663 and with our registered office at Carrer del Ficus 7, 03730 Javea, Alicante, Spain. Our UK trading address is 49-50 Eagle Wharf Road, London, N1 7ED, England.

We trade as “Global Careers Fair”.

Global Careers Fair (We) provides services (including online events, webinars and a job board) to help you find employment. In the delivery of this service, we will collect personal data about you, and technical data to improve your user experience. The new GDPR legislation about Data Protection means we are updating our Privacy Policy and Conditions of Use to make them clearer and more understandable, giving you specific information on how we collect, store, process and share your information. We also ask for your consent for how we contact you, and you will have the choice to change these settings on your dashboard.

* * *

### **1.Data collection**

1.1. We collect certain information or data about you when you use our website, https://www.globalcareersfair.com

This includes:

(a) data including your name, email address and a password, required to create an account;

(b) Information you provide on your profile page such as education, work experience, language skills, photo, location, et;

(c) Your IP address, and details of which version of web browser you use;

(d) Information on how you use the site, using cookies and page tagging techniques to help us improve the website. Please refer to our cookies policy (<https://www.globalcareersfair.com/cookie-policy/>) for more details.

(e) Messages and conversations you send and receive on our platform in connection with our Services, for example, conversations you have with recruiters during an online event.

1.2. This helps us to:

(a) improve the site by monitoring how you use it;

(b) respond to any feedback you send us, if you have asked us to;

(c) provide you with information and updates about our Services.

_1.3 Your Rights_

In accordance with GDPR (Subject Access Request), you have the right to access any personal information that we process about you and to request information about:

  * What personal data we hold about you
  * The purposes of the processing
  * The categories of personal data concerned
  * The recipients to whom the personal data has/will be disclosed
  * How long we intend to store your personal data for, and the criteria we use to determine this timeframe
  * If we did not collect the data directly from you, information about the source of the data

You can make this request in writing to , 49-50 Eagle Wharf Road, London N1 7ED, who will provide you via email details of our Subject Access Request procedures.

If you have a complaint about how a specific GDPR request has been handled please [contact us here.](https://www.globalcareersfair.com/gdpr-complaints-contact-form/)

### **  2.Data Usage**

We use your data to authorise your access to our Services and to provide you with a range of functionalities.

General considerations:

You will have control over how and when your information is visible. By supplying us with your details/profile, our contract with you is to support your search for employment by listing potential job opportunities from a variety of Employers. To do this, your status must be set so that your profile remains visible.

We will use your data, including the information you enter into your Profile page, to determine whether you may be a suitable Candidate for any of our Employers, to advise you on current suitable opportunities that we may make available for you in your search for employment, and to allow you to attend the online Employment Events we organise. We will also use your data to contact you via email with information and updates about current job opportunities and online events. You will have choices on your dashboard (<https://www.globalcareersfair.com/login/>) to set the content of our communications to you. Note that you will not be able to opt out of receiving communications from us regarding security and legal updates.

We will contact you every 12 months to remind you to update your profile/your current details (employment, experience, skills etc.) so that recruiters using our platform have access to your updated candidate profile and can accurately identify you as a candidate they may want to talk to.

You will have the option in your dashboard (<https://www.globalcareersfair.com/login/>) to set your status (“Actively seeking new opportunities”, “Open to new opportunities” or “Not currently seeking opportunities”) for the same purposes. You will have the option of setting your status to non-visible (“Not currently seeking new opportunities”) but by doing so, the functionalities from our system to you will be adjusted to reflect this. We will continue to have access to your profile in our capacity of data controllers. Please note status changes have a minimum term of 30 days duration.

Also, should your details not have been updated for a period of 36 months, and/or your account been inactive for 12 months, your account will be closed. This policy is aimed at the provision of our services to Employers being based on accurate, up-to-date information for the profiles of candidates.

If you start looking for new opportunities beyond that period, you will be able to create a new profile.

You will be able to check your status on your dashboard at any time and you will also have the choice to close your account (https://www.globalcareersfair.com/candidate-dashboard/delete-your-profile/) in a simple process. Please see our Data Retention policy below (3.6) for details on how long we keep your data under those scenarios.

We will use your data (if needed) to investigate any suspected violation of our Conditions of Use or this Privacy Policy and/or attempts to disrupt the running of our Services.

For our live events, you will register and share your data directly with Brazen Technologies, Inc. ([https://www.brazen.com](https://www.brazen.com/)), the provider (Provider) of the technological platform for our events. We will share your data with Brazen in order for it to be visible to Employers attending the event. Your data is shared with an Employer only once you join their queue on their event hub. Your data is not shared by us with Employers for reporting purposes post event as this is done on an anonymized basis. Please note that Brazen is a company based in the USA. Our due diligence process means we have reviewed their policies and measures aimed at keeping your data safe. Your data will be shared with Employer organisations, to the best of our ability, we have checked that their policies are also GDPR compliant and they should offer you similar safeguarding standards to those we offer you.

### **3.Data Storage**

3.1. We store the information and data you provide to us, or that we otherwise receive or collect about you (for example through the use of an API you can use to upload your profile to your account on our platform from another source) on our secure servers in Belgium. This data is backed up in Belgium. To increase the performance of our platform, we give access on a worldwide basis from regionally localized service providers to ensure fast and secure access. This CDN (Content Delivery Network) solution has state of the art security certification and security protocols. Details of the provider of this CDN can be found at <https://www.maxcdn.com/features/>.

3.2. Data you provide via our site for attending any online Employment Event, or as a Candidate in communication with a prospective Employer or agent, will be passed on to them. As they are located globally, your data may be consequently accessed and/or stored outside of the European Economic Area. As part of our due diligence, we will check that these parties receiving your data have policies in place that will offer you the rights and freedoms afforded EU residents under the GDPR.

3.3. You understand and accept that by submitting your information and data to us, you agree to your data being shared in terms of clause 3.2 above.

3.4. Transmitting information over the internet is generally not completely secure, and we can’t guarantee the security of your information and data. We implement safety safeguards designed to protect your data (such as HTTPS, encryption and password protection) and regularly monitor our own systems for possible vulnerabilities and attacks.

3.5. Data Retention policy: all data of yours that we hold, including your personal details, email communications, and any recorded online conversations, either directly with us or with Employers during one of our online events, will be deleted under the following scenarios:

(a) After 12 months of inactivity, or 36 months without updates to your profile and your account is closed,

(b) If you choose to close your account (which you can do on your Dashboard [here](https://www.globalcareersfair.com/candidate-dashboard/delete-your-profile/\).))

We will retain your data:

1) for auditing the use of our services,

2) if your details form part of a campaign in an anonymised format for which we are still running analytics for reporting purposes,

Retention and Disposal of your data is the responsibility of our appointed Data Protection Lead, and once at the end of the Retention period, destruction of your data will be completed.

Our Provider will retain your data for a period of 9 months after a live event, after which it is destroyed.

This Retention policy is communicated to both our Provider and all our clients (Employers) with whom we have shared your data; we will convey your status changes and ensure to the extent of our abilities that your choice to be removed from our own records is reflected on their databases in line with our Policy.

### **4.Data Sharing**

4.1. We won’t share your information or data that you submit to us with any external organisations for marketing, market research or commercial purposes. Sharing your information will be exclusively for the provision of our Services.

4.2. For live events, we will share your data with Brazen and it will also be shared with Employers with whom you chat during a live event, using safeguarding protocols such as https, encryption and password protection. While we cannot guarantee that Employers (or the Provider) will be subject to the same or equivalent legal requirements or practical safety measures as we are, we have taken all reasonable steps to ensure that they are aware we offer your data the protections afforded under the GDPR regulation and that we expect them to treat your data in the same manner.

4.3 For Webinars, the organization presenting will receive only the data you have shared with us when you registered for the webinar and the details of your submitted questions in the live Q&A.

4.4. We will pass on your information and data if we have a legal obligation to do so, or if we have to enforce or apply our Conditions of Use or other agreements. This includes exchanging information with government departments for legal reasons. It also includes the event where Global Careers Spain substantially has all of its assets acquired by a third party; in this case, personal data held by either/both entities about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.

4.5. You can [find out what information and data we hold about you](https://www.gov.uk/data-protection). You can request this by sending us an email to [info@globalcareersfair.com](mailto:info@globalcareersfair.com) or contacting Javier Benavides on +44 (0)203 301 4628, or by post at 49-50 Eagle Wharf Road, London N1 7ED.

### **5.Links to and from other websites**

5.1. This Privacy Policy only applies to this website and does not cover other websites that we link to. External websites you can be redirected to from our website are:

  1. Our Provider Brazen Technologies, Inc.
  2. Employers that work with us,

5.2. If you go to another website from our website, we recommend you read their privacy policy to find out how they use your data.

5.3. If you come to our website from another website, we will receive personal information about you from the other website. You should read the privacy policy of the website you came from to find out more about this.

### **6.Data controller**

6.1. For the purposes of GDPR, the Data Controller is Global Careers Fair, C/ Ficus 7, 03730 Javea, Spain. Our data protection lead is Javier Benavides, who is reachable at [datacontroller@globalcareersfair.com](mailto:datacontroller@globalcareersfair.com) or on +44 (0)203 301 4628, or by mail at 49-50 Eagle Wharf Road, London N1 7ED.

### **7.Data Breach Policy**

7.1. We take the security of your data very seriously and have measures and policies in place to protect it. Please refer to our Conditions of Use. While we cannot guarantee the complete safety of your data, in the event of an identified data breach, we refer you to our Conditions of Use (clause 10) for our policy and the measures we will take in response to that event.

### **8.Changes to this privacy policy/comments**

8.1. Any changes we may make to our Privacy Policy in the future will be posted on <https://www.globalcareersfair.com/privacy-policy/>. If you object to the updated terms of our Privacy Notice, you may close your account here (<https://www.globalcareersfair.com/candidate-dashboard/delete-your-profile/>) and you will cease accessing our Services under this contract.

8.2. Questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy Policy are welcomed and should be addressed to [datacontroller@globalcareersfair.com](mailto:datacontroller@globalcareersfair.com)
